[
    {
        "type": "multiple",
        "question": "The literal translation of Ireland's capital city 'Dublin' (Dubh Linn) is:",
        "options": [
            "Black Hill",
            "Black Sand",
            "Black Sky",
            "Black Pool"
        ],
        "answer": "Black Pool"
    },
    {
        "type": "multiple",
        "question": "Approximately how many people in the USA (who claim Irish Ancestry) claim to be able to speak Irish?",
        "options": [
            "5,000+",
            "10,000+",
            "15,000+",
            "20,000+"
        ],
        "answer": "15,000+"
    },
    {
        "type": "multiple",
        "question": "To which 'family' of languages does Irish belong:",
        "options": [
            "Romance languages",
            "Germanic languages",
            "Celtic languages",
            "Slavic languages"
        ],
        "answer": "Celtic languages"
    },
    {
        "type": "multiple",
        "question": "A Gaeltacht area is where Irish is spoken daily. Where is the only other country where you can find an officially recognised 'Gaeltacht'?",
        "options": [
            "Australia",
            "England",
            "America",
            "Canada"
        ],
        "answer": "Canada"
    },
    {
        "type": "multiple",
        "question": "What is the Irish translation for the name 'Aisling'?",
        "options": [
            "Angel",
            "Heaven",
            "Dream",
            "Prayer"
        ],
        "answer": "Prayer"
    },
    {
        "type": "multiple",
        "question": "Basic English sentence structure is 'subject (person) - verb (action) - object(noun)'. What is the basic sentence structure for Irish?",
        "options": [
            "verb - subject - object",
            "object - subject - verb",
            "subject - object - verb",
            "verb - object - subject"
        ],
        "answer": "verb - subject - object"
    },
    {
        "type": "multiple",
        "question": "Which Irish language pop song cover TG Lurgan has 8+ million views on YouTube?",
        "options": [
            "'Cheerleader' by OMI",
            "'Hello' by Adele",
            "'Wake Me Up' by Avicii",
            "'Despacito' by Justin Bieber"
        ],
        "answer": "'Wake Me Up' by Avicii"
    },
    {
        "type": "multiple",
        "question": "What phrase did Barack Obama say in his address to the Irish people in 2011 that translates as 'yes we can'?",
        "options": [
            "'Céad Míle Fáilte'",
            "'Is Féidir Linn'",
            "'Cáca Milis Blasta'",
            "'Féach Thall Ansin'"
        ],
        "answer": "'Is Féidir Linn'"
    },
    {
        "type": "multiple",
        "question": "In Irish language surnames, the word 'Mac' (e.g. McGrath, McCann, McAuley etc) means:",
        "options": [
            "Warrior of...",
            "Leader of...",
            "Son of...",
            "Brother of..."
        ],
        "answer": "Son of..."
    },
    {
        "type": "multiple",
        "question": "To make a noun in irish 'cute/small' you can add which diminutive suffix to the ending? e.g. 'Little Seán' would be:",
        "options": [
            "Seánón (sounds like 'Shawn-OWN')",
            "Seánín (sounds like 'Shawn-EEN')",
            "Seánán (sounds like 'Shawn-AWN')",
            "Seánún (sounds like 'Shawn-OON')"
        ],
        "answer": "Seánín (sounds like 'Shawn-EEN')"
    },
    {
        "type": "multiple",
        "question": "There were 111,000 Google searches for how to pronounce which Irish girls name in the year 2022 (implying that it's the hardest to pronounce correctly for non-Irish speakers)?",
        "options": [
            "Saoirse",
            "Caoimhe",
            "Aoife",
            "Siobhán"
        ],
        "answer": "Aoife"
    },
    {
        "type": "multiple",
        "question": "'Uisce Beatha'(ISH-KA BA-HAH) translates to 'Water of Life' and means which alcoholic spirit?",
        "options": [
            "Gin",
            "Rum",
            "Whiskey",
            "Vodka"
        ],
        "answer": "Whiskey"
    },
    {
        "type": "multiple",
        "question": "Which historic tragedy tragically caused a huge loss to the population of native Irish language speakers?",
        "options": [
            "World War I",
            "The Great Famine",
            "The 3rd Plague Pandemic (Bubonic Plague)",
            "World War II"
        ],
        "answer": "The Great Famine"
    },
    {
        "type": "multiple",
        "question": "In which year did English really begin to replace An Ghaeilge as the dominant language in Ireland?",
        "options": [
            "1751",
            "1801",
            "1851",
            "1901"
        ],
        "answer": "1801"
    },
    {
        "type": "truefalse",
        "question": "The film Irish Language film 'The Quiet Girl / An Cailín Ciúin' (2022) was nominated for an Oscar award for best international film.",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "type": "truefalse",
        "question": "More than 1 million people are learning Irish on the language app Duolingo (as of June 2021).",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "type": "truefalse",
        "question": "Welsh is considered a 'sister' language of Irish.",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "type": "truefalse",
        "question": "Aside from ancient Greece and Rome, the earliest examples of European literature are in irish.",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "type": "truefalse",
        "question": "Irish doesn't have words for 'yes' or 'no.'",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "type": "truefalse",
        "question": "Ireland is recognised as an officially bilingual country where ENGLISH is recognized as the first official language and IRISH as the second.",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "type": "truefalse",
        "question": "You can complete your driving test in Ireland through Irish.",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "type": "truefalse",
        "question": "Irish does NOT have masculine and feminine nouns like other languages do, such as French, Spanish, Italian etc.",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "type": "truefalse",
        "question": "It is possible to change your phone settings on the majority of mobile devices to display in the Irish language.",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "type": "truefalse",
        "question": "New words are no longer being added to the Irish Language",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "type": "truefalse",
        "question": "Like English, the Irish language features double vowels e.g.'book, seek' etc",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "type": "truefalse",
        "question": "Hollywood actor Cillian Murphy featured in an Irish-language short film.",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "type": "freeform",
        "question": "Type a number (digit) to represent the percentage of the Irish population who speak Irish as a first language",
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "type": "freeform",
        "question": "How many official distinctive dialects (distinct pronunciation, vocabulary etc) are there in the Irish language (enter a single digit)",
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "type": "freeform",
        "question": "The English language has 370 irregular verbs (Think ‘I go’ → ‘I went’!!) How many irregular verbs (as a number in digits) are there in the Irish language?",
        "answer": "11"
    },
    {
        "type": "freeform",
        "question": "Type the number to represent the current rank for Irish in Duolingos most popular languages: (e.g. '1' = '1st')",
        "answer": "16"
    }
]